And we will proceed for the tutorial of week two, uh,
with Diane Wakim from Latex Labon.
It'll be about the workflow that you will be using, uh,
during the digital board this week, uh,
having some tutorials on different software. So, enjoy, and thank you,
Diane.
Thank you, Ned. Hello everyone. So I'm Diane. If you haven't seen me before,
I'm the instructor in Leon. And so, yeah,
the idea today is to talk about what the general workflow
for your assignment this week will be,
and on the way I will show you different software. Um,
so let me share my screen.
Can you see my screen? Great.
So I will start with slides, but soon switch to the software,
but just for a, for general overview,
which you should know about from the lesson of, of yesterday. But, um,
so the idea is to, to get a three D model, uh,
you have different options for that. Uh, you can create it in Make Human,
which I'm gonna show you just afterwards,
but you could also create it from scratch.
If you're already familiar with three D modeling software, you can, uh,
three D scan yourself or someone else. You can find, uh,
a three D model somewhere on the web. Uh,
although the ID of the week is of course, to, uh,
experiment with the other techniques, but sometimes, uh,
what you wanna do for your project doesn't match with what you've, uh,
experimented with. Um, so once you have this three D model,
you are gonna want to maybe adjust it, clean it,
or prepare it in some way using a three D software.
I'm gonna do that for a short time, uh, with Rhino.
And then after that, from this three D model, you're gonna want to,
we're gonna want to go from three D to two D and in order to,
to be able to cut it, uh, on the laser cutter, um,
and then you're gonna of course cut on the sample,
your mannequin or body part. Uh, and then of course,
I mean, I put that as 0.5,
but it's obviously something you have to do along the way and not at the end.
Um, but yeah, so that's, uh, just to a quick reminder of the general workflow.
Um, so, uh, so just to,
to be clear, to come back on that.
So I'm gonna show you make Human a bit of Rhino and then three
D Slicer for flattening. Um, but these are options,
so you can also do this with other software.
So let's start with McCuin, um,
which you have the links for in the further download in the,
the email we receive for the week. Normally, um, what is,
so Make Human is is a software for three D modeling humanoid characters. Um,
it's free and open source. So it's, yeah,
developed and maintain by your community. And, uh, at first it,
it's used a lot to animate characters,
which we're not gonna delve into this week, but know that it's, uh,
also what it's made for. I've put the installation link back here.
I will send you the slides later. And imo. Um,
and now they have made a version that is more integrated with Blender.
So if you use, you might wanna use that instead. Um,
I'm gonna show you what it looks like. So I will send you these slides later.
Um, and in this, the remainder of the slides, I detail, uh,
all the main functionalities, which I'm gonna show you. It's, it's sort of a,
like, the slides will act as a reminder, uh,
but I'm gonna show you directly in the software. Um,
so to be clear as well, you don't have to do what I'm doing at the same time.
It's mainly just to show you that you, you can if you want. Uh, but I,
yeah, it's better if you experiment with it after, I think because I,
I will go quite fast on this, but make human looks like this. Uh,
when you open it first, you have this, uh, this human here.
You can, uh,
move around with the mouse by left click and or moving around
like this, or right click moving around or
zoom. I highly recommend for all three D software that you are going to use,
that you use a physical mouse and not the touch pad. Uh,
but that's just me maybe. Um, so
we're gonna create a kind of avatar three D three D person, uh,
for our, our workflow today.
The first things we want to change is normally the things
that, uh, you will see when you, you open software,
which is in the modeling tab up here. And in the main sub subtab,
these are, they're called macro elements,
which you can change with the sliders here. So this is a,
like, I don't know if you've played, uh,
video games with character creation, this is it,
but like with a hundred times more detail. Um,
so you can change, uh, here.
First just gender, age, muscle, the weight, the height,
things like that. And if you look at the bottom left of the screen,
I hope you can see that well on my screen. But you can have the,
uh, more detailed parameter of what you're changing. For example, for the age,
I can, I can watch it change, uh, here. 'cause on the slider,
you don't have a very clear, clear view of what you're doing. Um,
so you can, you can do, uh, yeah,
let's, uh, let's do some in the middle,
somewhere here. Um,
the proportions will change the proportions of, of, of the body,
but that's something you can adjust after, just,
that's just sort of like the first main parameters, uh,
which you're gonna tune later. Um,
these three sliders at the bottom are honestly
kinda weird. I don't use them much. They mostly change the skin color and the,
some facial features. Uh, and they're, they're linked together.
So yeah, I don't use them much. You can, you can have,
you can change the skin color, uh, in another part if you want.
And so all the features as well. Um, so yeah,
that's the main, first, main part.
Now let's talk about the next four subtabs, gender, face,
torso on the legs in each of these. For example,
if I go in, let's say face,
I'm gonna be able to,
let's zoom a bit on the face. Yeah,
I'm gonna be able to change a whole lot of parameters. Um,
on the, on the left side bar sidebar here, like the
shape of the face, et cetera. So for each of these tabs,
I hope it's not hidden by the zoom bar, but on the right hand side,
I can change the category and
go to mouth size and change like very
detailed parts of the body.
Like the left ear has like a hundred parameters,
so you can go very far with this. Um,
so you, you just have to play around with it, uh, for example, yeah,
and arms and legs, I can, uh,
I can increase the muscle mass in just one of the shoulders.
So yeah, this is completely up to you what you do with the, with this.
Um, in gender, you can change anything about the breasts,
regardless of the gender you choose here. Um,
there's a general category, but it, it's not, you can't really use it.
And they don't have any generals, so I'm not sure what it's used for. Um,
so yeah, this is, uh, I'm not gonna show every part of this,
but, uh, this is mostly just to show you everything you can do with, uh,
with this. Um,
and I can do someone that's not symmetrical at all. Um,
I, so if you ever, uh,
get lost somewhere on the view here, you can,
there are on, on the top bar here. Uh,
these are camera angles,
which you can use to get back to like the front view
or back view, et cetera. Uh, and these,
you can use to, if you, for example, if I changed, um,
if I changed the right arm
in some way, some, let's say very extreme way,
um, you can also do some that's realistic, of course.
And then I want to mirror this on the other side.
I can use these buttons here. You might or might not have the grid, uh,
at the back. That's just a display parameter here. Um,
and these are like undo or reset buttons.
Um, yeah,
just checking if there something else I wanted to tell you about on this,
don't hesitate to like interrupt me if you have questions.
I'm not sure I can see the chat, but don't hesitate to talk. Um,
yeah, so the next two tabs, uh,
random and custom and measure custom, we don't really need it here,
but random, you can randomize, uh,
a human for these settings.
So this will erase everything that you've done before. So don't do it if you,
uh, if you're getting attached to your avatar. Uh,
but I will do it now, so I could, I could, uh,
now it's getting randomized on the macros, the face and the body. Uh,
but I could say randomized also the heights, but not the macro
have, it's less symmetrical maybe.
So
this is endless. Um,
and in the measure subtab, you can, uh,
here actually enter specific measurements.
So on the right, right side bar, you have the categories.
And on the left side bar, you're gonna have every, um,
every measurement for the hips, hip circumference, the upper arm, et cetera.
So if you want to replicate, like measure yourself and replicate it,
you can, uh,
enter them here and then go back to these to
adjust things. So that's the main thing about,
so it's, it's very easy to use, um,
compared to other three G, it's not, it's not really three D modeling,
it's more parameterizing, uh, uh, three G avatar.
But, um, yeah,
just checking my notes. Yeah. So the next,
uh, part where you're gonna wanna look at is in the geometry tab.
Uh, actually the next three tab are gonna be important. Uh,
this one we don't use much, actually, but if you, if you,
if you explore the, the software fully, you might wanna know about it.
But you can, here, you can add clothes, uh, for example,
to your, to your avatar. Um,
you are not necessarily gonna need that for today or for this week,
but it's here. Same for the,
the hair. You can add hair
instead of bone tail, for example. So, yeah,
you have a, a bunch of things here. Uh,
you can decide if the eyes are high resolution or low resolution.
You can add teeth, tongue, eyebrows, eyelashes.
I'm not gonna add any of these for now. I would explain why later.
Let's keep the eyes though, because it's very quickly without the eyes.
Um, yeah, so that's geometries. And in,
in topologies you have some generic, uh, generic,
generic topologies, which will also erase what you've done.
So careful with that. Um, in materials,
you can, uh, you, so that's where you can change, uh, the skin color,
some of the facial features, uh, if you want. Um,
now the next one. So also tell me if I'm,
don't hesitate to tell me if I'm going too fast or too slow.
Um, so in, in pose, animate, um,
we have different subtabs. So the first one you're gonna land on is skeleton,
which we're not gonna use, um, for this week,
but that's where you want to add, um,
presets if you want to animate your character labor.
So I'm staying with none for this. And then impose,
uh, on the right side, I will, um,
I can choose a posture for my human.
Um, so yeah, there are a lot of them.
Um,
and then the last, uh, interesting tab,
probably this week, I guess, is community. Uh, so I, I,
as I was saying at the beginning, it's uh, open source software.
So a lot of people you included, if you, if you want later,
you can create assets, three D assets to add, to make human.
So if it's the first time you use the software,
you are gonna have to click on synchronize in the right side bar here.
And this can take some time to, uh,
to happen. Uh, but then when I'm, when I have the,
all the community assets synchronized, I can, I can find some, for example,
uh, update the list of poses, and,
and here I can see previews of, uh,
so human posture postures. Um,
this one
I can also find, uh,
different kind of hair or skin.
So what you just have to choose what you wanna,
what type of acid you want here, and then click on a date list,
it'll not update, um, on its own.
So hair is quite difficult to do. So there usually not very good, but,
uh, every item you download from this,
will you, you will find it back in the corresponding tab.
So for example, if I go to pro animate,
I'll remember the one I downloaded. I think it was this one. So yeah, they will,
they will display here the poses. Um,
but the, the hair I downloaded, I will find it here.
Which one is it? Yeah, this one.
Yeah, that's not good there for now.
So yeah, the, if you want, if,
if you want to have a specific, um,
specific posture or some, yeah, you can, you can look through the,
the community, um, community tab.
Um, what else can I tell you about this?
I think we
done with the creating the avatar for now, of course,
I'm not making now a very original person,
but feel free to spend some time on this when you, when you experiment.
Um, the last thing, the last important thing I, I,
I want to show you is how to save and export your work.
So this all happens in the files tab or with the three buttons you have
here. Um, so in order to save,
you have to,
the zoom bar is always not in good place.
You have to choose a, uh, the name, let's call it,
um, I'm not sure, have this one, but,
and then you can click on the three dots here to, to decide where it'll go.
Um,
name them, yeah, and then click on save.
It's a bit tedious, but yeah. So this will save your,
um, your work as mhm,
which is the working file format for a human.
So this is something that you can reopen and make human and work on it again,
but this is not what you want to go on with the rest
of what you wanna do. We're gonna want to export it in another format.
Um,
so these are mesh formats for three D objects.
You are gonna want to export it in S t L or,
or BG J format.
These are both very standard three D format that you are
gonna be able to open in any three D software.
If you're not sure which one you need exporting both,
just to be sure, I'm gonna
export it in tl.
Um, yeah, so I think,
do, do you have any questions on
I see the channel? No, no questions. I guess I'll go on. Um,
so now we're done with this. So I have this, uh,
you, you've probably seen during the, the lesson examples from,
from pastures or maybe we've explored others documentation.
But if I wanna do a mannequin for this week,
I'm not gonna wanna have the whole human. Um,
so now I'm going to show you how to cut body parts of your human in
Rhino. Um, so yeah,
so this part you can do in,
in in Blender or another three D software if you are more familiar with
it. Um,
there are a lot of rhino tutorials in the,
in the Fabric Academy class archive though,
so you are welcome to to, to watch them.
I'm not gonna go now in details about how Rhino works.
I'm just going to explain what I do as I go, but if you have questions,
we can come back to that at the end. That's no problem. Um,
so I'm gonna import, um,
I'm going import
this one. No, it's import the one we did just now.
So I imported my human so on.
And if you've never used Rhino,
I have these four panels which show different views of the same,
same space. Uh, so I can see from the right here that it's on, its back.
So I'm gonna just, uh,
pull up. Um,
and I like to have the perspective view rendered,
the,
if that's personal preference. Um,
so let's say I want to
have only the, the torso and,
and the head. Let's say I don't want the legs, uh, and the arms.
So I'm gonna, so I'm gonna show you a,
a quick way in rhino to cut, um,
body parts of a human. Don't do that to real people. Um,
so in Rhino,
you can either choose the options with the buttons from the
numerous menus, or you can type the comments in the top bar here.
So that's usually what I do, because I don't know where the buttons are.
I'm creating a line here that I'm drawing
in front of the place where I want cut.
So you will notice that I'm drawing it on the front view and on the perspective
view, it's actually not
just in front of the the three D object, but that doesn't,
and I'm gonna use a comment that's called, uh, mesh split.
So every, every time you write a command in Rhino, it's gonna ask you questions.
It's very important to read what it's telling you because
that's the whole point of it. So I type the command mesh split,
and it's asking me, select the objects you want to split to split.
I want to split this, this object, this human.
So I'm selecting it and then pressing enter.
And now it's asking me to select the cutting objects. So the, the,
the object with which I want to cut is the line.
So I'm selecting the line and pressing enter,
and it's telling me the result of the command one mesh was split in two total of
three meshes.
So now I can select the different parts
and I can move them around. I can delete them
and delete my, my line as well. Um,
yeah, so I'm gonna remove the arms as well.
This can do it with
several lines at the same time, more splits,
putting objects are both the lines
and yeah. So yeah, I'm removing this.
So there's a very important thing to know when you are using this
method that I'm showing you now, by going the perspective view,
you're gonna notice that, um,
the parts where I cut are are not closed, not closed off,
and you want to have a closed off object. It's very important.
So now when I'm selecting it,
it's telling me on the right that it's an open mesh and we want to close the
mesh. There's a, a way to do this,
which I'm going to use now,
which only works if the cut you made is flat.
Um, which is the case for us because for all the cuts, we use the
flat line. So I'm gonna use the cap.
So act asking me to select the objects I want to cap.
So I'm selecting this pressing enter.
It's asking me about options of this command,
but I don't want to change the options, so I just press enter again.
And it's telling me the result created four caps resulting in one closed object.
So now if I go back to the perspective,
I cannot see through it's closed. And when, when I select it,
it's telling me that it's, so
that's one way to do it. If you want to,
if you just want to cut parts and you know it's gonna be a clear cut like this,
you can also, I, I can quickly show you another way I can, for example,
if I want to, um,
let's say create, um,
like holes
inside my mannequin, for example,
I can have different ones. So I'm,
I'm placing them so that they're, uh, so that they're going through.
Uh, and I'm gonna use another command that's called, uh,
mesh Buan Difference. If you're familiar with the Pathfinder and Illustrator,
this is, you are gonna find similar stuff here.
So select the first set.
So the one I want to subtract from is this one.
Enter and select all the others, one with the other ones.
So, so now it's,
let's say, well artistic hold. Um,
so when I do it this way, I don't need to to close it.
It's already closed off, so I can can check it here. Close, meh.
So yeah, so I'm not gonna go into detail. It, it's,
it'll also depend a lot on what you want to do with your assignment,
what sort of, I'm actually gonna
remove that for the rest of the demonstration. But,
so, um,
just checking the questions
so we can export this now, just the were some other things. Oh,
no, yeah, it's something I didn't show you. Um,
if I move this around,
you'll see that I am leaving something behind,
and these are the eyes. Uh,
and there are actually separate objects. So this is a closed mesh,
and these are two, uh,
open mesh that we don't want for, for purpose now.
So I'm gonna delete them. Um,
and so that's why I didn't add the tongue and the teeth and the
eyebrows and eyelashes because it's 'cause they,
they would've been different objects as well. Um,
yeah, I'm gonna, now that I'm, let's say I'm,
I'm happy with the way it, uh, it turned out. I don't like this,
this cut very much, but let's see what it does.
Um, I'm gonna export this
by doing Export Selective and then selecting my object to export
again here. I want to export it in a way that's in a format that's
standard three D format. I'm gonna go with s t R here. Um,
I guess that was another one that we did
value export. So do not take this box.
Export open object. We won't closed objects always. Um,
so yeah, this is, this is something you can do in,
in other software. Oh, yeah.
Uh, so making a half figure or, uh,
is only possible on Rhino. It's not possible on, uh,
make a human.
Uh, so if you, if I want to cut it in half, for example. Yeah,
Like part of the figure,
Yeah, like, like, uh, like this, uh, yeah, so yeah,
you're not gonna be able to really, uh, do, uh,
three D Mod Modulization in, in, in ma Human.
It starts with a complete three D human,
and you cannot remove parts of it. If you wanna do that,
you're gonna have to do it in another Software Rhino or, or a Blender or,
um,
Would've been called make half a Human
Make. Exactly. Probably. So, yeah,
if I want to, yeah, you can have healthy human, so it's gonna be,
it's gonna be
need to cap it so that it's not,
but yeah, I kept, I kept this one and this one is below, you can see.
But yeah, so you're gonna have to do this in another software. But, um,
so actually I think I'm going quite fast. So I, maybe I have to show you this.
There's another software which you can use, uh, or you can,
I mean, you can use all of them if you want, but, uh,
I showed this one to my students, uh,
last year because it's very different in terms of f
it's a bit more like sculpting. It's called Mesh Mixer, and it's free.
So if I import, uh,
this one that I just exported from Rhino, uh,
in Mesh mixer, I'm going to be able to do things with brushes,
like, uh,
inflate some parts of the body. And this is more like, yeah,
this is more like sculpting. So you can, you can have,
uh, a different experience with this if you are more at ease with, uh,
this kind of software. And, and also if you want to go towards something that's,
uh, maybe less human, I guess. Uh,
and I think in this one you can also cut, uh, cut some parts,
I guess. Um, yeah,
main cut. I, I can also cut. Um,
so I guess I could do a half human in this. And, and it's a, if,
if that's the only thing you want to do, it's a simpler, um, software to use.
Yeah, I'm not sure if this is closed,
but yeah. So yeah, that's another software you can use.
I'm not sure I put it in the presentation, but I should,
so I will add it in this.
Oh, it's in the presentation. Great.
Okay. Um, so now that I've,
let's say I'm happy with how my human is. Uh, now,
uh, our next step is,
let me look at my own slides. Uh, yeah,
so we did the three D modeling and cleaning steps,
and now we want to slice it, uh, for laser cutting.
So I'm gonna use this software, which is called Slicer,
um, have slides on it.
So Slicer is actually initially used to be an add-on for Fusion 360,
but it also works as a standalone program.
It's deprecated, so it's not maintained anymore,
but you can still download it and use it, hopefully, uh,
but it might not work for everyone. Uh, if you are using,
uh, using Linux or
any UX distribution, uh,
Stephanie in the chat today sent an alternative that you can use if you're
familiar with that. And if you come across any other software that does this in,
uh, in this kind of not too complicated way,
we'll be very happy to hear about it. So this what, what,
what it does is that it's gonna simplify our work for,
for cutting a three D object into two D plans.
And it's gonna generate for us all the slots and assembly steps that we need.
So let's start it. It's here.
So when you start it up, it looks like this,
which is not much at the moment. Uh,
we're gonna import our five,
uh, wait, there's something I forgot to show you. I know,
but it's not, it's not necessarily, um,
it's not necessarily very important. It depends on what you wanna do.
But in Rhino,
there's a distance command that I can use to check the size of my
object, and I see that my object is 10 millimeters high.
So if you wanna do a full size mannequin,
you might want to scale it up. So scale,
let's scale it in. You can also do it in Slicer,
but it's better to have the right size initially.
Um, so it's 10 millimeters,
uh, let's increase it
by 50.
So yeah, 50 centimeters high.
I'm gonna say it's fine for my purpose. Now
it makes my test human. So, back to slicer,
there's not much you can do at first.
So import the import button is the only thing.
I'm gonna click on my test human,
and it's gonna import it face down,
which is not exactly what we want.
And this is actually something you have to change
when you import the software,
because here I can rotate, but I can only rotate it this way. So I'm gonna
import it again. And when I import it, you can see
that apart from the file here,
I can change the up axis and we need to put that to Z
for it to be upward.
Um,
so the first thing I need to do is check the units
and the size of my object. Right now it's in inches,
but I'm working in millimeters in rhino,
so I wanted to and make humans in millimeters as well.
So you have to change it here so that it's, um,
you also want to check original size if you wanted to be the original size that
you had in Rhino.
But if it's not the site that you want, you can also uncheck this and,
and change it. Here you have a,
a bit of a smaller one. I'm gonna change that. Uh,
sometimes in the tutorial you'll see uniform scale is of course,
so that when you change one, it changes the other accordingly.
So we have our human here,
and before starting to play with the different construction techniques,
the first thing we need to do is change our manufacturing settings.
So for this,
you can see here that there are different sizes of material,
like on a, like you would have on a printer,
and we're gonna add a new one. You are probably gonna need to add a new one,
except, uh, if you're using a,
a computer at the lab that already has all the, all the settings correct.
But for this,
you actually need to know the size of your laser cutter and the size of the
material that you're gonna use and the thickness of the material that you're
gonna use.
So now we're starting to get in the material side of things.
Um,
this is very important because when you are gonna generate the plans,
it's gonna take into account all of this. So to add a new one,
you just need to press here. It's gonna add in here,
um, and you can name it. For example,
I name mine with the name of the lab, name of the laser cutter
and material and thickness.
Let's say I'm adding a, which we don't have,
whatever. So very important, change the units here
and here, the length and widths of the material. So,
which is not necessarily the, uh, size, the length and widths of your laser,
but really of the board of material that you're gonna put in the laser.
Um, what did I put for this one?
I actually put the size of the lasers for mine, but we'll do that.
Let's say 800. Um, um,
600. Yeah.
So check with your lab. If you, if you don't know this, uh,
I'm gonna put four millimeters thickness, uh,
the margins are the margin it's gonna take while generating the plants.
Five millimeters is great, but you can play with that if you are,
if you want. And this one, the slot of set is very important,
but I will talk about it later.
So once you have added your new material in,
click done, and then you have to select it here.
It'll not be automatically selected.
So you have to see that it's the right one here.
And you can also see it's on the bottom of the screen.
So now we did all the,
all the drawing stuff. We can play with the construction techniques.
So they're all here. Uh, I will detail a bit, some of them,
but it's mostly for you to play with.
They are just some things I want to point out for some of the,
some of the techniques that are quite important to know.
Um, so the first one is stacked slices, um,
which is very aply named. It'll generate a bunch of,
um, slices that you will stack upon each other.
Um, and you see that as soon as I select a construction technique,
it shows me the plans on the right, I can, uh,
I can click on them and, and see them. If I,
if I click on one of the slices, I can see where it is on the, on the plans.
Um,
you can see that some of the parts are blue on
the, on the rendering here,
and the parts that are blue are when slicer considers
that this is not gonna hold, uh, when you build it,
which seems fair. I mean,
these very small parts might not stick.
Uh, so this is something that you, for example, for this, I could just decide,
I'm going to cut it this way and just not, not use this parts.
Or I could go back to my three D object and do a better cut on the arms
not to have such a sharp point here. So that, yeah, that's completely up to you.
Um, and you, you can see that on the plans,
it's shows you, uh, numbers as well.
So these are meant to be engraved on the pieces so that you have them when
you assemble, uh, the mankin.
If I go on the left here,
I can see this part assembly steps here. You can choose a material.
I can stick with cardboard for now, and I go back to the start.
I can see with the pieces highlighted, uh, on the plans on the right,
uh, how to build it exactly.
So this is not the most complicated, um,
construction technique to build if you have the numbers. Um,
but still the assembly steps are always useful.
Um, let's see. I can change the direction of the slices. Uh,
for example, I want to have stacked slices,
but a bit more interesting. Um,
it's gonna update on the plans here. Uh,
which can I tell you more about this?
Um, yeah,
so if I, I'm gonna reset the slice direction for this. Um,
here, under the stack slices selected, I can add Dass.
So it's gonna update on the plan. And so this is,
this is gonna add holes,
so you can put Dows inside so that it holds together without having to glue it
together. If you want to, for example,
build it and then unbuild it to transport it somewhere, and then build it again.
Um, so yeah, you can change the diameter according to what,
what kind of Ds you have can change the shape. Um,
let's see, another one, interlocked slices,
very popular construction technique for week two of fabric academy. Um,
so yeah, it's slices that are interrupt.
I can change here. So every time I choose a technique,
I'm gonna have different parameters to play with this here.
I can change here the count of, of slices,
the number of slices I can more here.
Um,
so now we have blue pieces, but we also have red pieces.
What does this mean? This means that there's a problem.
The red pieces, they can mean two things.
They can mean that part of the piece does not hold on
the, on your material sheet, that it's, it's gonna go over the edge.
It's too big. But here I can see that it's not the case. Um,
but the second option is that slicer considers that there's a problem with the
piece, that it's not gonna hold. So here on this piece, we can see,
for example here, the notch that's used to construct here.
It, it goes too far and it'll, it'll cut the piece. So we don't want that.
What we can do here is we can actually move them around. Uh,
so I guess the problem is with this one,
so I can select it and move it up. And so now,
so yeah, this one will change color here. Um,
and here we can see that this is up. Now,
now it still has a problem with the one with the arms. No,
I should have changed the arms before exporting it,
but we can work around that, but still have,
so it's sometimes a bit annoying to select the right size.
But let's move this one down, this one up
like this one. So generally,
you will want to have for this kind of construction technique,
I'm gonna delete this one. Yeah, so now this one is, is,
is not right anymore. So when you have a lot of red pieces,
in my case, uh, in this situation,
I would've gone back to the three D model and changed the arms or cut,
cut closer to the body maybe. But you can always, um,
play around here. Once you have, uh,
the slice selected, you can add more slices here as well as in the
sidebar left. And it's going to,
so you can play on this to add like more definition to one part of the
mannequin, less part in the less definition in another part.
Um, and of course I didn't show you,
but you can also change the slice direction for this.
So this is also something you can play with if, um,
to, to, to get rid of, of the red pieces. It, it might help in some cases.
Um,
where is the other access?
Yeah, so
the thing you have to take into account is, yeah,
so now I, I, yeah, my pieces are,
there's very few chances that there will be too big for the material I have.
But, uh, if you wanna have bigger one, pay attention to the,
the material size that you have available at your lab. Um,
so you can see here, uh,
that this is weird because we have the holes for
the eyes and the mouth, and we might not want that. We might want it, but,
um, maybe not. Uh, if so,
if you have the head, you might have cut off the head at this point.
This is something I usually deal with afterwards. So I know this part,
for example, it's gonna be red because of this big hole from the mouth,
but this is something you can remove before cutting. Um,
I will show you afterwards.
What else did I want to tell you about this construction technique?
So, yeah, contribute to the first one. The first technique,
you can put dowels or so, and they're, they're stuck on each other.
So we don't have the same problematic that we have here with the slots. Uh,
these, they need to go inside each other.
So remember when we added the manufacturing settings,
I told you about the slot offsets, that this is what you,
what you will want to edit if your slots don't fit
together because
it's going to generate the slot.
But maybe when your machine is cutting accordingly,
depending on the material you have,
you're gonna need a bit more ease to put the pieces together.
So this is what you, what you will want to, to, to edit.
What do we have? We have radial slices.
I'm gonna reset the slice direction for this one so you can see a bit more.
Um, yeah, so the radial slices, it has a center axis,
and then the slices around, depending on the material you,
you are using
this can be quite tricky to construct if it's a bit thick, uh,
and you have a lot of slices,
for example, here, like if I show you the assembly steps for this,
we're gonna start with this and then
insert all the radial sizes afterwards. And so
yeah, if you are, if your slots don't have enough ease,
you are gonna find yourself very frustrated with, um,
with the building of this. Same for the, for the interlock slices,
it's very tempting to have a lot of definition and put
a lot of, um, of slices,
but this is gonna be a living hell to build,
except of course, if you have a magical material. But, uh, yeah,
so I would advise not too many sizes for interal radio.
You also have curve. I'm gonna, um,
lower this number
a bit more. So curve is, um,
here, when you change the slice, you can change the slice direction.
You can also change, see there's this curve here,
and what this will do is that the slices will kind of follow the
curve. Um,
so this can do some pretty funky things, um,
but it's, I find it nice, but, uh, you have to be really careful.
If, if, um,
if the thing you're doing is gonna be realistic to construct,
I would advise you to always check the assembly steps.
And if it seems okay or doable to you,
then it should be okay. But for example, on this one,
these parts seem pretty weird to me. Let's reset this.
Um, the last one,
I guess like interlock the curve is folded panels,
which is a kind of a, like a folding exercise.
So you can see here,
so here this one is in red because it goes outside of the plan as you can
see, and there's no way it's gonna fits in the plan. Um,
these are
good for a specific type of material like paper
or very thick cardboard.
The settings you have here is the vertex count.
So if I increase it, let's say to three 50,
I'm gonna have a bit more definition and a bit more pieces.
I would advise if you do this, that you do not do it in the original size,
because it's gonna be very complicated.
And then lower this as well. Yeah.
So this is, this seems okay,
I still have some red pieces in this case for this technique,
I can use this option, which is called add or remove seams. And I can,
I can change it. Look up here.
Lemme see what it does.
Yeah, it didn't help much.
So yeah, this is not a very easy one, but, um, it's nice. I will,
I can show you examples of this. So it's very,
it's, it's, it's not easy because it's very tedious to assemble. Um, so you can,
you can change the joint type. Um, first you, you,
you only have these small triangles. Uh,
this one, yeah, tabs, like this might be better.
So this one is, yeah, it, it, it,
it would cut on the laser and it would precut the parts where you have
to fold. Um,
the last one is three D slices, but it's not, um,
useful for us right now. Uh, yes,
one thing I forgot to show you in stacked slices, um,
let's get bigger,
is that you might want to
not use so much material for this one and make it hollow.
So if I click on modify point here and click on Hollow,
and let's say hollow, it's like this.
Yeah. And so now you see the plan is, uh,
yeah, it doesn't take as much material because if I want,
I can optimize it and put some of the smaller pieces inside the bigger
ones, so it's not gonna take up as much material.
So Slicer does a very bad job of optimizing the plans.
So that's something you will have to do. That's a,
an additional step that you have to take even more if you follow it
and have it like this. Um, so
what else are there questions
again? Can, let's see. No, no questions.
I hope I'm not overwhelming you. Um,
what else could I forget?
That's all for now, for Slicer. The,
there is the one very important thing. Um,
it's, and it's how to save and export. And in our,
in this case,
they are gonna be for very different purposes because
we have our plans that we're gonna want to export for laser cutting,
but we also want to save our work
by going on the big slicer logo and going to save, um,
save to my computer.
And this is going to save it
as a work file of slicer that you can open again
and you will want to open it again. Uh oh.
Yeah, you don't want to hollow this one, of course. Um,
yeah, might have able to. Yeah, it's not updating it. It's, no,
it's not updating the plans. T update this. No,
nevermind. Uh, that's not what I wanted to show you.
But what I wanted to show you is that what happens most of the time is,
so you tinker with it a lot, you change the slice direction,
the slice counts, the slices position,
and then you export your plans and you close slicer.
And then when you cut the pieces and you have to assemble it,
you don't have the assembly steps. And this is,
this has happened to countless students over,
over the past years.
So remember to save your work in slicer so that you can go
back to see the assembly steps. This is very important.
Yeah. So you want to save it.
And then for the export part, we want to get the plans.
So these plans are like, of course, if your plans are read, read like this,
don't export them. Is there a question? No,
I heard someone. Um, so yeah,
if your plans are read like this, don't export them, of course. Uh,
but if you click get plans here on the bottom of the left side bar,
you can choose the,
the format here that will depend on
the laser cutter you have, um,
or how you want to treat the plans or optimize the plans before or,
or, or there in P D F O or D X F. Um,
and then you have to choose the, of course,
millimeters and export to my computer.
So if you choose D X F, it's gonna export a zip with all the files.
If you export A P D F,
it'll probably export to just one P D F with all the pages.
And
so I'm not gonna use these plans for the when I will show you next.
Um, but yeah,
now you might think that it's over, but it's not.
There's something else very important I have to show you. Um,
so I, I think I must have better plans
somewhere here. Yes. So
now I'm gonna, uh,
try to optimize a bit the plans and, uh,
generate a fine so that I can do a test cut for my, uh,
for my, my model. So I'm doing this in Rhino,
but it's for me, not necessary. All you need is, um,
software that does, uh, a a two D pictorial software.
So you could do this in Illustrator or in scape,
or I do it in Rhino because I, uh,
don't know how to use Illustrator or the other software.
Um, but you, you will, you just, just, I'm doing it just to show you the, uh,
the ID of what I'm doing. Um,
I, I think I have to them here like this.
I do this,
put this as well.
Why is it not sure
higher? So,
so I'm gonna explore this. So it's a two D plan. So, uh,
this box here, if it's not tick, it's gonna do where things, um,
I want to have the top view. So yeah,
the important thing is to open your plan in somewhere
where you can edit it.
I'm gonna export the other page. So,
so this is from another mannequin that I did, but it's quite similar.
It was the interlock slices. So this one is very obvious,
um, like how to optimize it,
because I can see with my eyes that these pieces
can completely fit on here. So I can do this manually,
but there are, I, I can, I will send you in, in Mattermost afterwards,
uh, or put them in the presentation. There are, uh,
websites or software s vg Nest is one I think, or maybe some,
uh, escape, um,
add on where you can optimize the plan.
But if you don't have a lot of, like, for example here, I just have,
I just had two, two material boards. So it's,
it's not much to do with by hand. Um,
here is the step where I'm gonna want to remove the
three PIs. Uh, from
here I wait on, right now,
I actually have to draw all the lines.
This better.
So I'm gonna remove good points from these
eyes, for example, or, or you might wanna keep them.
That's of course completely up to you. Uh,
the mouth here, if you want to have engraving,
some engraving on the mannequin,
that's a good step where you can add some design here to be engraved.
That's a step where you might wanna to
change the, uh, yeah, in the chats, the grasshopper definition,
rhino also works nicely ah, yeah, for the, um,
for optimizing the plans, I guess. Um,
thanks. So yeah,
if you want to have some, uh, add some design to engrave on the pieces, uh,
that's, you can do it now. And that's also a step where you can, um,
change the colors if you need, of the lines, for example,
or laser cutter in Leon, uh,
the cutting lines or in red and the engraving lines in black. So yeah,
that's something you have to, to see, um, according to your lab.
And one important thing that you need to do is that you need
to make a test cut before cutting your home. And can,
so for example, I can take a part of it here,
um, this, and
so wait, I'm gonna actually do it on the copy of that.
So I take a part where there are notches
very important, and I want to
take only this,
and let's take another one.
It's not very important if,
if those are pieces that are actually supposed to match,
because all the slots are the same.
So it's important to have,
but what I wanna have is
actually
this, I'm gonna wanna cut this on my laser cutter first and check
if these slots fit into each other. Um,
this is important for two things, actually. It's important. Um,
it's important to check the slots,
but it's also important to check the settings of the laser cutter if you have,
haven't used it before for this material, for example. So you might,
like, if you're using cardboard from the lab and used it before,
you still need to understand what it is. But, um,
yeah, so this is important for the settings of the laser cutter and to check the
notches, because if you cut your whole mannequin on,
I don't know how many boards and the slots don't fit,
you're gonna be very frustrated and you won't have any more material. So yeah,
really important to do that. So this can be part of your, um,
maybe your laser color training,
or you can prepare some files to check, to check for that.
Um,
so in talking about the materials, also keep in mind,
um, what you have at the lab, um, for example,
in your region, usually provide around six sheets of cardboard for a student.
So check with your opinion instructor. Uh,
be mindful of what material there is for everybody, uh, before,
uh, this is useful to know at, at the, at the step where you're in slicer.
And so it's so that you don't get 15 sheets in your
cutting layout. Um,
yeah, I guess I can stop sharing.
Um, so
let me see. I think, yeah, and then when you,
when you cut it, you can assemble it and, and then that's it,
you're done for your assignment for the week. Um,
but again, so all, all these things that I showed you here are, are options.
Uh, for the slicing part. There's also a way to do it in Rhino. Uh,
I think there's a tutorial in that in the, in the class archive,
and I think it was from my year. Um,
so yeah, don't hesitate if you have other options,
if you discover other things, we'll be very happy to,
to see that in your documentation as well. Do you have any questions?
Are you completely overwhelmed? Are you okay?
Please someone say something?
I have a question. I have a question. They, yeah,
Thank you.
Regarding the tutorial tomorrow and, uh, like not the tutorial,
like the lesson, are we doing already like some, um,
like demo versions before our final or it's like laser cut directly?
Is there, I don't think there's a global tutorial tomorrow. I think it's, uh,
locally with your instructor learning how to use the laser cutter.
Uh, but let me check the, the,
Oh yeah, I think, yeah, 'cause I'm not in class now, and I think my, um,
my tutor said that we're gonna do like scanning and then laser cutting.
I don't know, I just, I wanted to say something.
Thank you. Hopefully
We can like have a, a trial of something else
Then. Yeah, so usually, um, usually on,
on for this week, uh, or maybe you,
maybe some of them of you did it this morning,
but usually on Thursday you're going to learn how to use the laser cutter at
your lab. Um, mm-hmm. And, uh, do a, a demo of three D scanning,
uh, depending on what, on what you have at the lab for three D scanning. Um,
I think every lab has kind of different things. Um,
And,
And so yeah, usually on, on on Thursday you, you prepare your files,
you do test cuts, you learn how to use the laser cutter,
and then on Friday you should have a, uh,
dedicated time slot to, to use the laser, um,
to use the laser to, to cut your, your mannequin and then assemble it, um,
on either on the same day or, or, or later. Yeah,
keep in mind to yeah, document,
take pictures and yeah,
all that. Thank you.
Um, I have, yes.
So how are we supposed to like, insert,
for example, I,
something how I supposed insert it into Rhino or I,
my,
So I, I can't hear you very well, but I think you're asking about when, uh,
about the three 3D scanning.
Yeah, how, how are we gonna like insert it the data into the softwares.
So if you, if you do a three D scan, you and, and,
and you are happy with your three D scan object, um, how it,
how it look like, looks like, uh, you, you, you can use that object.
You don't need to create one and make human or, or, or anywhere else.
You can directly, uh, I mean if you three D scan something,
usually you have to clean it up because the three D scanner picks up
sometimes other parts or some of the parts are not exactly like you want.
So you, you might want to use a three D modeling software to clean it up,
to cut some parts to get it exactly like you want.
So I would say it replaces the make human part,
but not the cleaning part that I showed in, in Rhino. Um,
yeah. So that, that's one way to get a a three D object. Oh, wait, no, I'm,
I'm gonna share my screen again. Actually, I, I forgot that.
So I will send you the slides which recap everything. Uh,
but I also had, uh, some examples from the previous years.
And I think now that I've shown you every, all this,
you should be able to tell which technique they use. Like this one is,
uh, radial slices. This one is stacked on the side.
This one is interlocked. Um, these two, this one,
on the first one, there are, uh, the same,
like this one is stacked with two different materials. This one is, uh,
interlocked and then folded for the prosthetic legs.
Um, this one is, uh,
stacked and it's hollowed, and there's a lamp inside, which is very cool. Uh,
this one is in, uh, plexi, but with the, uh,
the sides painted, this one is folded panels, um,
folded panels leg. This one is engraved with organs.
So, yeah, uh, I, you will have them in the, the slides I sent you.
And they're all, um,
linked to the documentation they come from. So yeah,
don't hesitate as well to to check
documentations from the previous years and just to get a feel of what you can
do, what you might wanna do. Yeah,
I'm sorry. You're welcome.
So I was actually wondering mm-hmm. So it,
it is possible to have something two D going directly to the
laser cut without going through working a three D object.
Um, well, I'm gonna say depends on what you know already,
what your background is, because the goal this week is also to learn about this,
um, mm-hmm.
And how to go from a three D object virtual of, of,
or real life if you scan it and then to T two D and then to
reconstruct it in real life.
So I guess check with your local instructor if,
or remote instructor, if they're okay with that according to your background.
But yeah, I'd say the goal is also, I mean, for example, if you,
uh, you can experiment with three D scan and put it in your documentation and
say, look, I have three D scans. Uh, I don't know, my, uh,
my hand and it looks like this, but I'm not gonna use it for the assignment.
Instead I'm gonna use, uh,
this three D object that I found or created with, with some other things.
So it's also a matter of, uh,
how you wanna approach the assignment and what you have to do for,
for the assignment.
So let's say look at the checklists that Noria showed in your event.
Mm-hmm.
Okay. And I,
one last thing I saw in the materials that you could use like textiles,
like cotton or hemp, is,
do you have like any examples of those?
In, in my human?
Yeah. Or I, I got confused.
Uh, you can, you can add clothes. There are a bunch of clothes, but it's not,
you're, you're not going to,
it's not very precise in term of rendering of textiles or materials.
Um, what you could do, if you want to go more into that,
I'm gonna add new ideas and new, new software, but, uh,
is use CLO three D for example, which is much more, um,
goes much deeper in terms of materials rendering and, and textures.
Uh, yeah, but it's more for garments, and it's not, it's not,
you can't make a, your three D person in clothes, three D,
but if you're interested in the materials side and the textile texture side,
like
The manufacturing part of the project, should it, like, it's, it's not in,
in textiles.
Oh. Like you can laser coat a fabric. Oh, you can laser coat a fabric,
but it's not gonna hold too construct a mannequin, uh mm-hmm.
Except if you, I guess you could harden it in some way, but, uh,
no, usually this assignment is done with cardboard because it's quite
a bit crazy.
Okay. Thank you.
You're, you're welcome.
Well, I guess if there are no more questions. Let me look at the chat.
Ah, yes. In your documentation you're gonna have to put your, uh,
fabrication files. Uh, but for the three D models, you can,
uh,
you can upload them to something like Sketch Fab and then embed it like you
would embed video in your website. Uh,
but the two d laser coding plans you can upload on your documentation.
And, um, and I'm also very happy to try this with you tomorrow, Mario.
Well, I guess if there are no, I have to, I have not ideas, so, oh, yeah.
I guess I, uh, this's something I can tell you as well. Yes. Um,
you are gonna have so many ideas, uh,
And some don't. That didn't work. It doesn't work, I think.
Yeah. But I mean, if you, you,
you won't have time to do all your IDs every week,
but write them down anyway.
And you will have IDs for Lifetime at the end of the academy.
But yeah, try to not get lost in the assignments. Yeah.
Thank you. Yeah,
and if you have more questions about the software or anything,
I am always reachable on, on Mattermost or Right.
Just right in the Digital Bodies channel. And yeah,
have a, have a nice, uh,
time of day wherever you are. I guess we can stop the recording,
maybe.